<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[John Murphy Institute]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[John Murphy Institute]]></description>
        <link>http://johnmurphy.institute/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 19:41:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://johnmurphy.institute/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 19:41:21 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BLARG]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BLARG</h1>,<p>October 10, 2017</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/872ac8dc-5f2a-43b8-9f2b-cf049a849f9c.jpg">,<p>Here’s a timeline that lead me from the <a href="http://www.stupidcreatures.com/" title="">Stupid Creatures</a> to where I am now.</p>,<p>2003 Started making sock monsters in Okland, CA, and peddling them from shop to shop. Got some coverage in Ready Made Magazine (now defunct, I guess). That led to some coverage in other magazines. <a href="http://www.stupidcreatures.com/" title="">Stupidcreatures.com</a> went live. Started taking custom orders. Lark Books, now <a href="http://larkcrafts.com/" title="">Lark Crafts</a>, caught wind of my efforts and offered me a craft book contract.</p>,<p>2004 Got really poor living off of sock monster income and odd jobs. Moved back home to North Carolina to write <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Stupid-Sock-Creatures-Lovable-Cast-off/dp/1579906109/ref=asap_bc?ie=UTF8" title="">Stupid Sock Creatures</a>. Got a studio in downtown Asheville.</p>,<p>2005 Stupid Sock Creatures came out. Started teaching classes and giving lectures nationwide.</p>,<p>2006 TV spot on HGTV’s That’s Clever (now also defunct.. I must have the magic touch). Moved into a studio in <a href="http://www.riverartsdistrict.com/" title="Yuppified">Asheville’s River Arts District</a>.</p>,<p>2007 Started counseling kids as a one-on-one for a 5th grader with high-functioning autism. Continued making monsters for shows and sales. Still wasn’t a living, but I kept trying.</p>,<p>2008 Got my second book contract from Lark and started writing <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Closet-Monsters-Stitch-Creatures-Clothing/dp/1600596045/ref=asap_bc?ie=UTF8" title="">Closet Monsters</a>. <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/reports/2017/04/13/430424/2008-housing-crisis/" title="Thank you Wall Street">Housing bubble burst</a>, people got poor and stopped buying art.</p>,<p>2009 Income getting desperate, I kept making monsters, but started looking for other work in the counseling field. Was offered a contract for <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Revelations-Stupid-Creatures-John-Murphy/dp/0982075456/ref=asap_bc?ie=UTF8" title="">Revelations and the Stupid Creatures</a>, and began working on that book.</p>,<p>2010 Became a wilderness camp counselor. Life officially changed. Kids in need mattered more to me than art ever did. Closet Monsters hit the shelves.</p>,<p>2011 Became an intensive in-home counselor, working with kids and families in poverty-stricken rural areas in western NC. Landed book contract #3, and started writing <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Return-Stupid-Sock-Creatures-Evolutions/dp/1454702842/ref=asap_bc?ie=UTF8" title="Fan Favorite">Return of the Stupid Sock Creatures</a>. Began working with <a href="https://www.landofnod.com/" title="">Land of Nod </a>on various toy lines.</p>,<p>2012 Became a day treatment counselor for kids whose behaviors got them kicked out of school. More toy lines with Land of Nod. Return of the Stupid Sock Creatures hit the shelves.</p>,<p>2013 Promoted to lead day treatment teacher at my agency. Started thinking about grad school. More toy lines with Land of Nod. Worked with <a href="http://secretagent23skidoo.com/" title="">Secret Agent 23 Skidoo</a> to pitch a cartoon property to Cartoon Network.</p>,<p>2014 Dad diagnosed with leukemia. Moved closer to where dad lives. Became a juvenile justice officer with NC’s department of public safety. Became a godfather.</p>,<p>2015 Became certified as a juvenile justice officer.</p>,<p>2016 Started my graduate degree with <a href="http://learn.regent.edu/" title="">Regent University</a> to become a mental health counselor. First biological nephew was born.</p>,<p>2017 Working out how I want my career to look when I graduate. Dusting off the website. Still making monsters when I can.</p>,<p>If you’re curious about anything else, glean my <a href="http://johnmurphy.institute/social-media-ugh" title="Not posting my FB">social media resources</a> or email me.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://johnmurphy.institute/this-is-john-i-havent-posted-to-this-website-in-a-very-lon/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1c8b29f2-bad7-4924-929f-050df4f4de98</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 18:45:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is John]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This is John</h1>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/36ff7c40d8ed0c87d65577bbf6ee98dcdb0cd7d8.jpg">,<p>John Murphy is an artist and author, formerly of www.stupidcreatures.com. In his plush toy heyday, John wrote <a href="https://www.amazon.com/John-Murphy/e/B001K8GFA0/ref=dp_byline_cont_pop_book_1" title="">several books about making stuffed toys</a>. He is currently earning his master’s degree in mental health counseling and trauma therapy, and plans to continue serving at-risk kids.</p>,<p>With studio life at a current ebb, John serves his state as a juvenile justice youth counselor, working with amazing, flawed, redeemable, chaotic, incredible, marvelous youngsters who add unspeakable dimension to his life, and change his perspective regularly.</p>,<p>What else..</p>,<p>John has 2 brothers and 2 sisters. He collects <a href="https://tfsource.com/" title="">transformers</a>. He has 3 nephews, one biological and two who adopted him. He has one goddaughter. John has 2 parents and 2 stepparents, but not in that order. John likes to bike and work out, but doesn’t do it as regularly as he should. John loves to bake breads and sweets, and is said to have inherited that knack from his great grandfather. John likes to put faces on things. He loves to draw. And these days he cannot stop crocheting.</p>,<p>John is a redeemed sinner, and handles that ongoing process <a href="https://www.firstrpcdurham.org/" title="">here</a>.</p>,<p>His <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/registry/wishlist/YBGTYLJCP4GR/ref=nav_wishlist_lists_1" title="">birthday</a> is very soon ;)</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://johnmurphy.institute/this-is-john/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">59bd2517-6809-4e82-a12c-302890639aa1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 03:50:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Social Media. Ugh.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Social Media. Ugh.</h1>,<p>Here’s my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/stupidcreatures/featured" title="">youtube</a>.</p>,<p>Here’s my <a href="https://twitter.com/StupidCreatures" title="">twitter</a>.</p>,<p>Here’s my <a href="https://www.instagram.com/johnmurphyinstitute/" title="">instagram.</a></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/87037aee-9177-497f-9bc3-52ae58e30e29.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://johnmurphy.institute/social-media-ugh/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3c9597d2-8832-4418-9c58-675d4cd39172</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 20:41:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I am testing out the gallery capabilities of this software.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>I am testing out the gallery capabilities of this <a href="http://thegrid.io/" title="">software</a>.</h1>,<p>The help page of The Grid tells me that to create a gallery, all one must do is upload at least nine images. Well here are twelve. We shall see the results.</p>,<p>These are images I used for an easy project I designed for <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Craft-Camp-Over-Projects-Kids/dp/1454709006/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1507210887&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=lark+books+craft+camp" title="">Craft Camp</a> (Lark Crafts, 2015).</p>,<p>What I like about this gallery feature is that all the images are condensed into one place. What I don’t like is that when you click on an image, you’re taken to a new page where the images are displayed together again. I would rather this software allow thumbnails and expanded images. I must see what can be done. </p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2166a702-e146-4484-bbbb-f5721c04bbc6.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/09157a20-6917-4c89-8eb1-d16078202042.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/62802537-49d2-4b21-bfc2-b296c591f816.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9dcc5fb2-f843-4aef-906c-115f99caca38.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/0c58a624-76c9-40b1-9c77-4911536aa672.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a667937a-a06e-4921-8f3b-cf2209d49c5a.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/666489c3-33ed-4c32-8ec0-826f899fa3ce.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b5a21c20-455c-4d1f-8d6f-4c9fd4edc44d.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2ff42fa2-f793-4d99-b51d-23cddde2c0e0.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/241a6257-ddd7-4125-9d3f-d7427bd96858.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/e0e6589c-e741-481b-a9a7-5e3015c2413c.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9d2184bc-43a0-406f-a7e8-69f6b3072cb5.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://johnmurphy.institute/i-am-testing-out-the-gallery-capabilities-of-this-software/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">62160a03-6ddd-446e-be5c-744060ae7e97</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 13:43:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shop]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shop</h1>,<p>At the moment, John has a degree to earn and a full time job that he adores, so new and custom works are on pause. But if you loved what you saw at the <a href="http://stupidcreatures.com/" title="">old website</a>, you can keep the embers glowing by checking out these links!</p>,<article><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/379d1d0d4381b5100ec68c39029acb24a5565a57"><h1>Giant Plush Dragon</h1><p>Shop Green Giant Stuffed Animal Dragon. This giant plush dragon may look ferocious, but you don&apos;t have to worry about it leveling any villages.</p></article>,<article><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/ee4192508d3ed0c27889cde64bb8e2d9de904373.jpg"><h1>John&apos;s Books</h1><p>Visit Amazon.com&apos;s John Murphy Page and shop for all of his books. Check out pictures, bibliography, and biography as soon as he takes the time to write them. </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://johnmurphy.institute/buy-my-stuff/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">96346633-c43d-4039-a85e-a09a58efdb77</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 19:39:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>